Ryan O'Mullan

Irish, Single, 28 years old São Paulo - Brazil

Email: omullan.ryan@gmail.com

Skype: ryanomullan

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/ryanomullan/pt

Summary

Trilingual English / French / Portuguese

International Experience: France, Germany, Brazil

Experience with Sales, Project Management and Web Development in the Health, Finance and Digital Marketing Industry.

Interest in the areas of Business Intelligence, Data Science, Startups, Business, and Web Development.

Education

Master: Web Engineering -- Senac São Paulo, Brazil (03/2015 - 12/2016)

Bachelor: Commercialization of Products and Industrial Services- - Université Toulouse III, France (09/2011 - 09/2012)

DUT: Electronics and Industrial Informatics - Université de Limoges, France (09/2009 - 06/2011)

Skills

IT

- Python, Django, Postgres, SQL, MongoDB, Git, Linux, HTML, CSS.
- Moderate knowledge: Javascript, Java, Spring, R, C, Delphi, AWS and Docker.
- Google Analytics, Photoshop and Excel.
 Business
- Business Intelligence, CRM, Sales, Negotiation and International Development.
- MailChimp, Microsoft Office e Sage CRM.

Languages

- Native English- Lived in Ireland for 12 years
- Fluent French -- Lived in France for 10 years
- Fluent Portuguese Currently living in Brazil
- Basic German -- Lived in Germany for 2 years
- Basic Spanish

Professional Experience

Software Engineer - PagueMob, Brazil (04/2016 - Today)

- Building financial products from scratch using Agile Methodologies.
- Working in close connection to Mobile and Design teams to define product design and functionality.
- Monitoring and reporting the overall progression of the team to the CEO.
- Main Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Scala, Play Framework, Python, Postgres, Redis, ActiveMQ, SQLAlchemy, Docker and AWS.

Project Manager - Boom Financial (04/2017 - Today)

- Coordinating resources for execution of projects.
- Ensuring that all projects are delivered on-time and within scope.
- Developing project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.
- Reporting project performance.
- Creating and maintaining comprehensive project documentation.

Web Developer - Freelance (12/2013 - Today)

- Building responsive websites for mobile and desktop devices.
- Managing websites, social media and marketing email.
- Main Technologies: Python/Django, Postgres, Javascript, Bootstrap, Git, Heroku, MailChimp.

Web Developer - Zenvia Mobile Results, Brazil (04/2015 - 04/2016)

- Development of RESTful APIs for an AdServer
- Creating B.I. reports
- Automating various tasks using Python scripts.
- Monitoring and creating reports for the performance of advertising campaigns.
- Validating advertising material: Images, HTML and JavaScript.
- Main Technologies: Python/Django, Javascript, MongoDB, Postgres, Django Rest Framework, Git and highcharts.js

International Account Manager - nal von minden GmbH, Germany (04/2012 - 10/2013)

- Selling medical equipment to French and International distributors.
- Managing Key Clients.
- Customer and technical support.
- Creating promotional and marketing material
- Participating in international fairs and visits to clients.

Marketing Assistant - Alias Invest, France (11/2011 - 02/2012)

- Creating marketing material for the company's website.
- Benchmarking competitors.

ERASMUS Internship - University of Regensburg, Germany (04/2011 - 06/2011)

- Designing the layout of circuit boards with CadSoft EAGLE.
- Programming microcontrollers in C.

Professional University Project - Université de Limoges, France (09/2010 - 03/2011)

 Creating and designing an educational desktop program using Delphi 7 for a school of polyhandicapped children.